NATE AZEVEDO

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Full Stack Software Developer with experience designing and developing websites from client to server side. Exceptional communicator with a reputation of demonstrating professionalism in team environments. Testing is a priority and I program in a test conscious manner. Well versed in the following technologies: React, Python, Javascript, Node.js, SQL, SQLAlchemy, Redux, Flask, Express, PostgreSQL, HTML, and CSS.

EDUCATION

Springboard Software Engineering

Mar. 2020 - Current

700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

Boise State University Bachelors Biology 2020 June 2014 - Dec. 2016

EMPLOYMENT

Springboard Software Engineering Fellow, Fellow

Mar. 2020 - Current

700+ hours of hands-on course material, with 1:1 industry expert mentor oversight, and completion of 4 in-depth portfolio projects. Mastered skills in front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms.

St. Luke's Hospital, Certified Sterile Processing Technician, Boise, ID

Feb. 2017 - Mar. 2020

Held the title of Team Huddle Leader which entitled facilitating group discussion in order to improve department communication and workflow. Trained new hires and observing nurses on proper sterilization techniques to ensure uniformity in following standard operating procedures.

SKILLS

Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Node, Flask, Express, SQL, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, Testing, Git, Jinja

PROJECTS

Irrigate July 2020 - Current

Flood irrigation is a time consuming task. I have designed and created a device and web app which significantly lowers human effort and stress while flood irrigating. Currently in prototype stage. Ready for implementation summer 2021.

Technologies used: Arduino, React, Express, PostgreSQL, Python, Javascript, JWOT, CSS.

Feel Aug. 2020 - Current

Concepts practiced: user flow design, dynamic templating, back end routing, database design, ORM querying, RESTFUL API design, unit and integration testing, JSON usage, session storage.

Technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, Flask, SQL, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, Jinja.

Warbler - Twitter Clone Oct. 2020 - Nov. 2020

Twitter Clone website of which I was responsible for refactoring. Provided experience working with large code bases with many features.

Features implemented: logout, edit profile, adding likes, unit and integration testing.

Technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS, Python, Flask, SQL, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, Jinja.

AWARDS

Magna Cum Laude, Boise State University

Dec. 2016

VOLUNTEERING

Faces of Hope, Volunteer / All around helper

Boise, ID

July 2017 - Nov. 2019

Applied interpersonal and emotional intelligence to comfort victims of domestic and sexual abuse. Provided resource guidance to aid victims toward acquiring psychological and financial support.

Performed over 20 hours of victims assistance training, accredited by the Office of Justice.